export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2013 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following is an art form of the ancient Japanese?",
A: "Sacrificial bronze vessel",
B: "Silk screen painting",
C: "Bronze jars",
D: "Bird-shaped vessel",
answer: "B. Silk screen painting",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The process of attaching a board cover with glue to the spine of a book is termed",
A: "padding",
B: "wapping",
C: "sabbing",
D: "backing",
answer: "D. backing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Who are the outstanding artists of the high renaissance period?",
A: "Giotto, Caravaggio and Van Gogh",
B: "Cezanne, Monet and Rembrandt",
C: "Leonardo, Raphael and Michelangelo",
D: "Picasso, Michelangelo and Braque",
answer: "C. Leonardo, Raphael, and Michelangelo",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following is not a physical property of colour",
A: "hue",
B: "form",
C: "value",
D: "intensity",
answer: "B. form",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Select an element of design from the following",
A: "Balance",
B: "variety",
C: "harmony",
D: "shape",
answer: "D. shape",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. An object that absorbs all the colours of the spectrum will appear",
A: "black",
B: "brown",
C: "grey",
D: "white",
answer: "A. black",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Burin is a tool for",
A: "batiking",
B: "engraving",
C: "etching",
D: "printing",
answer: "B. engraving",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The most suitable binder for watercolour is",
A: "lacquer",
B: "gum Arabic",
C: "vinegar",
D: "carpenter’s glue",
answer: "B. gum Arabic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. In an art studio, a donkey is",
A: "a model for figure drawing",
B: "an animal for landscape painting",
C: "a combined stool and a drawing board",
D: "a dummy on which a model sits",
answer: "C. a combined stool and a drawing board",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The appearance of grey-baft is enhanced by",
A: "bleaching",
B: "mercerizing",
C: "scouring",
D: "sizing",
answer: "B. mercerizing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following helps to identify a style in lettering",
A: "size",
B: "texture",
C: "typeface",
D: "length",
answer: "C. typeface",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Visual art education fosters creativity by",
A: "promoting citizenship qualities in artists",
B: "creating an awareness of the role of art",
C: "helping artists to think and act uniquely",
D: "encouraging the appreciation of cultural heritage",
answer: "C. helping artists to think and act uniquely",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of these ancient civilizations wrote on papyrus",
A: "Egyptians",
B: "Greeks",
C: "Indians",
D: "Romans",
answer: "A. Egyptians",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Artists create caricatures to depict",
A: "beauty and elegance",
B: "humour and satire",
C: "confusion and rage",
D: "peace and harmony",
answer: "B. humour and satire",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Round hog bristle is to in-laying as flat hog is to",
A: "outlining",
B: "detailing",
C: "filling-in",
D: "blocking out",
answer: "D. blocking out",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The technique of placing new painting on either side of the old is",
A: "juxtaposition",
B: "superimposition",
C: "superposition",
D: "transposition",
answer: "A. juxtaposition",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A green shape placed on a red background will create",
A: "balance",
B: "contrast",
C: "dominance",
D: "harmony",
answer: "B. contrast",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The ancient Chinese executed sculptures of animals mainly to",
A: "clay",
B: "metal",
C: "stone",
D: "wood",
answer: "B. metal",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The minsereh figure is the art form of the",
A: "Baule",
B: "Dogon",
C: "Kissi",
D: "Mende",
answer: "C. Kissi",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. How many intermediate traids are contained in the twelve-point colour",
A: "one",
B: "two",
C: "three",
D: "four",
answer: "C. three",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Pottery making was prevalent in Greece during the",
A: "archaic period",
B: "geometric period",
C: "classical period",
D: "Hellenistic period",
answer: "B. geometric period",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Ancient mosaics were mainly done in",
A: "glass",
B: "terra-cotta",
C: "tesserae",
D: "wood",
answer: "C. tesserae",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A suitable medium for outdoor sculpture 15",
A: "bronze",
B: "crav",
C: "plaster",
D: "plasticine",
answer: "A. bronze",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Akuaba is the fertility as Ibeji is to",
A: "ancestral veneration",
B: "agricultural rites",
C: "dead twin",
D: "water spirit",
answer: "C. dead twin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The most suitable support for intaglio printing is",
A: "wood",
B: "lino",
C: "glass",
D: "metal",
answer: "D. metal",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The Polynesians based their art works on",
A: "everyday activities",
B: "war and conquest",
C: "foreign cultures",
D: "beliefs and practices",
answer: "D. beliefs and practices",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following countries produced soapstone sculptures?",
A: "Cote d’Ivoire",
B: "Sierra Leone",
C: "Ghana",
D: "Guinea",
answer: "B. Sierra Leone",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following is based on the principle of repulsion of grease and water?",
A: "Lino cut",
B: "Intaglio",
C: "wood cut",
D: "Lithography",
answer: "D. Lithography",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. A characteristic feature of Greek sculpture in the Archaic period is the",
A: "sculpted human figures were in correct proportion",
B: "human figures were given movement and flexibility",
C: "sculpted naked sportsmen were in different postures",
D: "forms of statues were stiff and symmetrical",
answer: "D. forms of statues were stiff and symmetrical",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Pecking the outline of figures is a technique of",
A: "painting",
B: "engraving",
C: "appliquéing",
D: "etching",
answer: "B. engraving",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Colours that tend to advance in a painting are",
A: "bright",
B: "cool",
C: "dull",
D: "weak",
answer: "A. bright",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The Indian preserve sacred relics in the",
A: "Palace",
B: "shrine",
C: "stuna",
D: "temple",
answer: "C. stuna",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following is a direct printing",
A: "Frottage",
B: "Wood-cut",
C: "Lino-cut",
D: "Screen",
answer: "B. Wood-cut",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. An egg yolk is used as a binder for",
A: "acrylic",
B: "gouache",
C: "tempera",
D: "watercolour",
answer: "C. tempera",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The absorption of dyes into fabrics is enhanced when the fabric is",
A: "bleached",
B: "sized",
C: "soaked",
D: "washed",
answer: "C. soaked",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. In silk screen printing, the ink is forced through the mesh by the use of",
A: "brayer",
B: "pliers",
C: "squeegee",
D: "roller",
answer: "C. squeegee",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The process of preparing hides and skin into leather is",
A: "embossing",
B: "scrapping",
C: "skinning",
D: "tanning",
answer: "D. tanning",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Fixative is a preservative for drawings done in",
A: "chalk",
B: "ink",
C: "poster colour",
D: "watercolour",
answer: "A. chalk",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The purity of a colour is its",
A: "hue",
B: "intensity",
C: "opacity",
D: "value",
answer: "B. intensity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following ethnic groups produces the nomoli?",
A: "Baule",
B: "Dogon",
C: "Mende",
D: "Senufu",
answer: "C. Mende",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]